A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1964-1965
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1964-1965
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.681
This collection consists of 27,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library on 28 August 1968.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Contents List
- General Files, 1964-1965
  - "A - Am" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - "An - Az" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Academic Deans 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Academic Freedom and Tenure (see University Tenure) 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Adams Papers (see also Madison and Jefferson) 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Admissions - Applicants 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Admissions - General 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Admissions - Reports 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Advisory Panel on ROTC Affairs 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Air Force Academy - Board of Visitors 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Air Force and Air Force ROTC 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Albemarle County Public Schools 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Alumni News 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Chapters Planned 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Houston Chapter 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Roanoke Chapter 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Fund 1964-1965 (Box 2)
  - Alumni - Medical 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - Alumni - Speeches (see also Speeches and Articles) 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Association - General 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - American Association of University Professors 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - American Council on Education 1964-1965 (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "A" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "B" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "C" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "D" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "E" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "F" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "G" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "H" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "I" (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "J" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "K" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "L" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "M" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "N" (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "O" (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "P" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "Q" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "R" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "S" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "T" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "U" (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "V" (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "W" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions - "X - Y - Z" 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Architecture - General 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Architecture - Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Army - General 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Army - Judge Advocate General's (J. A. G.) School 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Army - Judge Advocate General's (J. A. G.) School Building 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Army - ROTC 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Art 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Art Commission 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Colleges 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - General - Folder # 1 1964-1965 (Box 5)
  - Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - General - Folder # 2 1964-1965 (Box 5)
  - Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - Circular Letters 1964-1965 (Box 5)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Astronomy 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - ACC 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football Coach 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - General 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Grants-in-Aid Program 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Invitations to Games - Board of Visitors, State Officials, etc. 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - NCAA 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - 3 - 2 - 2 Committee 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football: Wake Forest Game - 19 September 1964 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football: V. P. I. Game - 3 October 1964 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football: Army Game - 17 October 1964 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Football: N. C. State Game, Homecoming, Band Day, and Commonwealth Day- 24 October 1964 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - University of North Carolina Game - 14 November 1964 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Athletics - Maryland Game - 21 November 1964 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Atomic Energy Commission 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - Audit Reports 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - "B - Bm" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - "Bn - Bz" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - Berkeley, Francis L., Jr. 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - Biology - Blandy Farm 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - Biology - General 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - Biology - Mountain Lake 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - Biophysics 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - Budget Office - Budget Requests 1964-1965 (Box 8)
  - Budget Office - Capital Outlay 1964-1965 (Box 8)
  - Budget Office - Director's Office 1964-1965 (Box 8)
  - Budget Office - Miscellaneous Information 1964-1965 (Box 8)
  - Budget Office - New Positions Needed 1964-1965 (Box 8)
  - Budget Office -Operating 1964-1965 (Box 8)
  - Buildings and Grounds - General 1964-1965 (Box 8)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Progress Report 1964-1965 (Box 8)
  - Bureau of Population and Economic Research 1964-1965 (Box 8)
  - Bursar (Tuition, fees, employee benefits, etc.) 1964-1965 (Box 8)
  - "Ca - Ck" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - "Cl - Cz" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Calendar for Deans 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Calendar of Events 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Catholic Center 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Cavalier Daily 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Center for the Study of High Education at the University of Virginia 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Chancellor for Community Colleges 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Chemistry 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Chemistry Building 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Children's Rehabilitation Center (see also Rehabilitation Center) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Civic Beautification (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Civil Defense 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Civil Rights 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Classics 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Clinch Valley College - Building Program 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Clinch Valley College - General 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Clinch Valley College - Monthly Reports 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Clinch Valley College - Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - College Entrance Examination Board (see Admissions) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Colonnade Club 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Commerce - General 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Commerce - Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Ad Hoc Committees 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Ad Hoc Committee - Admissions Criteria for Branches and Community Colleges Community 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Academic Legislation 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Admissions 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Administrative 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Arboretum Advisory (see also Blandy Farm) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Architectural Advisory 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Athletic Advisory 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Blandy Farm Advisory 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Cabell Hall Addition 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Calendar and Scheduling 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Calendar of Events (see also Calendar of Events) (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Catalogue 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Cemetery 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Chapel 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Chemistry Building (see also Chemistry Building) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Clinch Valley College Advisory (see also Clinch Valley College) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Clinch Valley College Library Building 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Community Colleges Advisory (see also Chancellor) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Community Colleges Building (see also Chancellor) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Community Relations 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Computer Center (see also Computer Center) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Contractual Relations 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Danforth Fellowships 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Distinguished Professorships for the Faculty of Arts and Sciences 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Distinguished Professorships in School of Engineering and Applied Science 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Dormitory 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Dormitory Counselors 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Duke Property 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Extension (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Faculty Rules 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Field House (see also University Hall) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Fine Arts (Internal and External) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Fellowships (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Foreign Students 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Fraternities (see also Fraternities) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Fulbright Grants 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Graduate (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Graduate Degrees in Summer (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Gwathmey Award (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Hospital Accounts 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Housing 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Institutional Analysis (see also Institutional Analysis) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Inter-University Committee on Travel Grants 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - J. A. G. School Degree (see also J. A. G. School Degree folder inside Law folder) (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Library (see also Library) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Library Building 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Married Student Housing (see also Copeley Hill) (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Master Plan 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Master's Degree in Public Administration 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Medical Affairs Policy Board 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Medical Center Planning Committee (see also Medical Alumni) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - on "Morea" and Colonnade Club Room (see also University Houses - "Morea" and Colonnade Club) (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Objects of Art 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Official Greetings 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - on Organization and Functioning of Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Orientation 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Page-Barbour and Richard Lectures (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Patrick Henry Advisory 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Physics - Administration, Operation, Financing, Y Personnel Practices Institute Shop 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Processions 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Public Education 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Public Occasions (see also Finals) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Public Relations (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Radiation Safety 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Registration 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Research (see also Research) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Research and Training Funds Policy (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Research in the Humanities 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Rhodes Scholarships (see also Rhodes Scholarship) 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Scholarships, Loans, and Employment 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - School of General Studies - Eastern Shore Branch Advisory 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Snack Bar 1964-1965 (Box 9)
  - Committee - Scientific Research 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Space Astronomy (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Special Lectures (see also Lectures) (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Special Professorships 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Status of Research Associates and Other Senior Non-Faculty Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Student Activities 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Summer Session (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Teacher Education (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Traffic Control (see also Traffic Control) 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Transfer Credits for the Undergraduate Schools of the University Committee 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Tree (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - University Committee on Students 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - University Press (see also University Press) (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - University Records 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - University Union (see also Newcomb Hall) 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Virginia Quarterly Review Advisory (see also Virginia Quarterly Review) (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Virginia Status of University Students 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Wilson Gee Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Comptroller (see also Budget Office) 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Computer Center 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Construction Sciences Institute (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Cooper, Weldon (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Copeley Hill (Married Student Housing) 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Council of Southern Universities (see also Southern Fellowships Fund) 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 11)
  - Darden, C. W., Jr. 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - Dean of the University (see Student Affairs) (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - Deans Luncheons 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - Degrees 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - Economics 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - Education - Division of Education Research 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - Education - Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - Education - Rehabilitation Center 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - Educational Aid for State Employees (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - Educational T. V. 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - Emeriti 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - Endowment Fund 1964-1965 (Box 12)
  - Engineering - General 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - Engineering - Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - English 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - Enrollment (see also Registrar) 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - Faculty - Five Year Faculty Staffing 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - Faculty - General Faculty 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - Faculty - General (Miscellaneous) 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - Faculty Orientation and Reception 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - Faculty Tenure (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Academic Faculty 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Committees of (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Departmental Chairmen 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - General 1964-1965 (Box 13)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel, "A - H" 1964-1965 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel, "I - N" 1964-1965 (Box 15)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences - Personnel, "O - Z" 1964-1965 (Box 15)
  - Federal Legislation 1964-1965 (Box 16)
  - Federal Relations 1964-1965 (Box 16)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships 1964-1965 (Box 16)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Cross 1964-1965 (Box 16)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Dupont Regional 1964-1965 (Box 16)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Fulbright 1964-1965 (Box 16)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Love 1964-1965 (Box 16)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes 1964-1965 (Box 16)
  - Finals 1964-1965 (Box 16)
  - Ford Foundation (see also Madison Papers re: Proposal) 1964-1965 (Box 17)
  - Foreign Student Advisor (see also Student Affairs) 1964-1965 (Box 17)
  - Fraternities 1964-1965 (Box 17)
  - Founder's Day 1964-1965 (Box 17)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 17)
  - General Assembly (see also Legislative Program) 1964-1965 (Box 17)
  - General Studies 1964-1965 (Box 17)
  - General Studies - Branches Proposed 1964-1965 (Box 17)
  - General Studies - Eastern Shore Branch 1964-1965 (Box 17)
  - General Studies - Eastern Shore Branch Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Lynchburg Branch 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Lynchburg Branch Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Madison Center 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Northern Virginia Center 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Patrick Henry Branch 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Patrick Henry Branch Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Richmond Center 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Roanoke Center 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - General Studies - Roanoke Center Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - Geography (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - Geology 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - Gilmer Hall 1964-1965 (Box 19)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1964-1965 (Box 19)
  - Governor's Office 1964-1965 (Box 19)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1964-1965 (Box 19)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences - 3 Years Master's Degree Program 1964-1965 (Box 19)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration 1964-1965 (Box 19)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration - Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 19)
  - Graduate School of Business Administration - Sponsors 1964-1965 (Box 19)
  - Guggenheim Foundation 1964-1965 (Box 19)
  - "H" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 20)
  - Higher Education Study Commission 1964-1965 (Box 20)
  - Highway Department 1964-1965 (Box 20)
  - History 1964-1965 (Box 20)
  - Honors Program (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 20)
  - Honor System and Honor Committee 1964-1965 (Box 20)
  - Hospital (see Medical Center) 1964-1965 (Box 20)
  - Housing 1964-1965 (Box 20)
  - Housing re: Miss Betty Cocke (see also Housing Committee) 1964-1965 (Box 20)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 20)
  - Information Services (see also Public Relations and Development) 1964-1965 (Box 21)
  - Institute of Early American History and Culture 1964-1965 (Box 21)
  - Institute of Government 1964-1965 (Box 21)
  - Institute of International Education 1964-1965 (Box 21)
  - Institutional Self-Study 1964-1965 (Box 21)
  - Institutional Analysis, Office of 1964-1965 (Box 21)
  - Inventions and Patents 1964-1965 (Box 21)
  - Invitations - "A" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "B" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "C" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "D" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "E" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "F" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "G" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "H" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "I" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "J" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "K" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "L" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "M" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "N" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "O" 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "P" 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "Q" 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "R" 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "S" 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "T" 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "U" 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "V" 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "W" 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "X - Y - Z" 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Thomas Jefferson Award 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Thomas Jefferson Center 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation (see also Founder's Day) 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation - Board 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Thomas Jefferson - Miscellaneous (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Jefferson Papers (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Jefferson Society 1964-1965 (Box 23)
  - Joint Office of Institutional Research 1964-1965 (Box 24)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 24)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 24)
  - Law 1964-1965 (Box 24)
  - Law - J. A. G. (Judge Advocate General's) School Degrees 1964-1965 (Box 24)
  - Law - Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - Lectures 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - Legal 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - Legal - Estates, Deeds 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - Legislative Program (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - Liberal Arts (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - Library 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - Library - Board of Alderman 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - Life Sciences Building (see Gilmer Hall) (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - Longwood Foundation 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - "Ma - Me" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - "Mi - Mz" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - Mace 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - Madison Papers 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - Marine Science 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - Markle Foundation 1964-1965 (Box 25)
  - Mary Washington College 1964-1965 (Box 27)
  - Mary Washington College - Building Program 1964-1965 (Box 27)
  - Mary Washington College - Financial 1964-1965 (Box 27)
  - Mary Washington College - Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 27)
  - Master Site Plan 1964-1965 (Box 28)
  - Mathematics 1964-1965 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center 1964-1965 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center - Hospital 1964-1965 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center - Hospital Monthly Statistical Reports 1964-1965 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center - Hospital Operating Budget and Reports 1964-1965 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center - Hospital Reports on Current Operations 1964-1965 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center - Medical Board of Hospital (see Committees) 1964-1965 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center - Medical School 1964-1965 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center - Medical School Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 29)
  - Medical Center - Nursing 1964-1965 (Box 29)
  - Medical Center - Nursing Personnel 1964-1965 (Box 29)
  - Mental Health 1964-1965 (Box 30)
  - Modern Languages 1964-1965 (Box 30)
  - Monroe Foundation and Library 1964-1965 (Box 30)
  - Monroe Papers (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 30)
  - Music 1964-1965 (Box 30)
  - SEE BOX 45 FOR REMAINDER OF "N" FOLDERS
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - Circular Letters 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges - International Letters 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - National Commission on Accrediting 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - National Defense Education Act (also National Defense Student Loan) 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - National Historical Publications Commission (see also Madison and Adams Papers) 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - National Science Foundation - Institutional Grant for Science 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - Navy 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - Navy - NROTC 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - Negro Enrollment (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - Newcomb Hall (see also Committee on University Union) 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - Newcomen Society 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - News Letter 1964-1965 (Box 31)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1964-1965 (Box 32)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO Visiting Professors Program) (folder empty) 1964-1965 (Box 32)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1964-1965 (Box 32)
  - Office - Files 1964-1965 (Box 32)
  - Office - General Stores Purchases 1964-1965 (Box 32)
  - Office - Information 1964-1965 (Box 32)
  - Office - Invoices, Requisitions, etc. 1964-1965 (Box 32)
  - Office - Supplies 1964-1965 (Box 32)